# Paul Janson

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pauljanson002/

Github: https://github.com/Pauljanson002 Personal website: pauljanson002.github.io Personal Email: pauljanson002@gmail.com Professional Email: paul.18@cse.mrt.ac.lk

Mobile: +94-776495354

## Research Interests

My research interest lie in the conjunction of computer vision and deep learning. Particularly I am interested in the performance of deep learning based vision models in the 'wild'. Removing the current limitations of deep vision models and learning with limited labels. Specifically continual learning, zero shot learning and domain generalization

### **EDUCATION**

## University of Moratuwa

Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering- GPA: 3.90/4.2 (First class) Nov 2019 - Jul 2024

#### Research Experience

### University of Moratuwa

Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

Oct 2022 - Present

 $\label{lem:condition} Undergraduate\ Thesis\ \hbox{--}\ Advisor:\ Dr.\ Thanuja\ Ambegoda$ 

• Generalizing Neural fields using Meta learning: Working on a meta learning based approach that helps to generalize neural fields to be able to reconstruct 3D object with single view. view proposal

## King Abdullah University of Science and Technology

Research Intern - Advisor: Dr. Mohammed Elhoseiny

Thuwal, Saudi Arabia Jan 2022 - Nov 2022

- Inductive continual zero shot learning with semantically guided random walks: Developed a method that combines creativity based and semantically guided random walk based losses in continual zero shot learning. To avoid the usage of unseen class semantic information at training time.(view paper)
- A simple baseline for continual learning with pre-trained model.: Developed simple model based on Nearest mean classifier that shows great performance on standard continual learning benchmarks questioning the usage of continual learning on simple benchmarks.(view paper)

# ScholarX Mentorship Programme

Remote

Mentee

May 2021 - Nov 2021

• Vision Transformers for continual learning: Performed an independent study to use vision transformer architecture in continual learning. Developed a dynamically expanding architecture with compact transformer modules (view)

#### Publications

• A simple baseline that questions the use of pre-trained models in continual learning: Accepted at NeurIPS 2022 Workshop on Distribution Shifts (view)

Paul Janson, Wenxuan Zhang, Rahaf Aljundi, Mohammed Elhoseiny

• Continual generalized zero shot learning through semantically guided generative random walk: In review - ICLR 2023 (view)

Wenxuan Zhang , Paul Janson, Divyansh Jha , Kai Yi , Ivan Skorodov, Mohammed Elhoseiny

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

## University of Moratuwa

Teaching Assistant

Moratuwa, Sri Lanka Aug 2022 - Present

1 . . . 1 .

• Theory of Computing: Worked in grading assignments and exams of undergraduate students

## Professional Experience

#### Yarl IT Hub

Jaffna, Sri Lanka

Intern

Feb 2018 - Oct 2018

o Aki E learning platform: Worked in content creation and website administration

## Relevant Courseworks

- Linear Algebra: A+
- Applied Statistics: A+
- Calculus: A
- Differential equations and applications: A+
- Intelligent Systems (AI): A+
- Research and report writing: A+

## SKILLS AND STANDARDIZED TESTS

- Programming Languages: Python, Javascript, Java
- Deep/Machine learning tools: Pytorch, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Numpy
- **TOEFL iBT**: 106/120
- General computing: UNIX, SLURM
- Experiment tracking: WandB

## SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

- Appeared in Dean's honors list for 5 semesters : 2018-2022
- Mahapola Merit Scholarship for Undergraduate education: 2018-2022
- Bank of Ceylon Nanajaya Scholarship for Undergraduate education: 2018-2022
- POH Scholarship by Zagro Asia Limited, Singapore for Undergraduate education: 2018-2022
- Dialog Merit Scholarship for Undergraduate education: 2018-2022
- Governors Award for best performance in GCE A/L (3rd in the country): 2017

#### Volunteering and Professional Service

- Student representative for CSE department: 2019-2020
- Volunteer translator for open.uom.lk: 2022
- Volunteer at Yarl IT hub non profit organization: 2018-2022